<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on Sailing Lucy</title><link>https://lucy.hamburg/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Sailing Lucy</description><image><title>Sailing Lucy</title><url>https://lucy.hamburg/images/lucy_logo.png</url><link>https://lucy.hamburg/images/lucy_logo.png</link></image><generator>Hugo -- 0.147.2</generator><language>en_UK</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 22:26:38 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://lucy.hamburg/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sailing on River Elbe</title><link>https://lucy.hamburg/posts/elbe/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 19:48:46 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://lucy.hamburg/posts/elbe/</guid><description>&lt;p>Elbe means &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tide">tide&lt;/a>. So sailing goes with the current, ideally adapted to the tide 😉&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Lucy’s home port is Hamburg. Hamburg lies on the Elbe and sailing begins right outside the harbour entrance. In my case, the entrance to the Rüschkanal harbour at Finkenwerder.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Elbe is a tidal area; the current does not always flow downstream as in all rivers but, thanks to the flood tide, sometimes flows upstream. To have fun and make progress, one generally follows the tide. It sets the rhythm and the timings for departure and arrival.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Delivery from Hayling Island</title><link>https://lucy.hamburg/posts/delivery/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://lucy.hamburg/posts/delivery/</guid><description>&lt;p>Lucy was built in England and was launched for the first time in Lymington on 7 March 1979. I also purchased Lucy in England. Robin Milledge was a great help to me during the purchase, and I can highly recommend him as a surveyor! See &lt;a href="https://rozelmarine.co.uk">Rozel Marine&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At Hayling Island, the yard &lt;a href="http://haylingyacht.co.uk/">Hayling Yacht Company&lt;/a> carried out a refit. Structural issues were addressed and the engine was overhauled.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="winter-in-the-boat-shed">Winter in the Boat Shed&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I undertook some of the work myself and visited the yard several times. The yard is beautifully situated. Working in the cold boat shed was no pleasure. Most boats in England are kept outside over winter, so I was glad to be able to work indoors.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>